<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>talks | Home</title>
    <link>https://mststats.github.io/tag/talks/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mststats.github.io/tag/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>talks</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>&amp; copy 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mststats.github.io/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>talks</title>
      <link>https://mststats.github.io/tag/talks/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>INQUA 2019</title>
      <link>https://mststats.github.io/post/inqua/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mststats.github.io/post/inqua/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INQUA 2019 is  the congress of the International Union for Quaternary Research.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Dr. Niamh Cahill and Prof. Andrew Parnell I co-convened a session on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.oxfordabstracts.com/events/574/program-app/session/4680&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bayesian statistical analysis methods for paleoclimate data&lt;/a&gt;.
This session was very successful in that we had a full room and 6 great talks, along with a poster session. Hopefully we managed to convince
some of the audience that Bayesian methodology is the way to go for inverse problems such as climate reconstruction with multiple sources
of uncertainty!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eurodeer XI</title>
      <link>https://mststats.github.io/post/eurodeer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mststats.github.io/post/eurodeer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eurodeer is a scientific network for data and knowledge sharing on wild roe deer populations.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was honoured to give a keynote talk on Social Network Analysis to a group of conservation biologists and
others working in the area of monitoring and researching wild animal movements. People from 33 different
research centres and environmental institutes come together once a year to work on projects (&amp;ldquo;pagers&amp;rdquo;)
and to establish data sharing mechanisms and write papers. There is an appetite to do more social network
analysis, which is where I fit in. In the first instance I will collaborate on a single paper analysing
deer movement patterns and social network behaviours in reaction to the establishment of feeding stations.
Telemetry and other data will be collated from a range of terrain, climate, and vegetation scenarios.
The aim of the project is to apply Social Network Analysis techniques to ascertain how human
provided feeding stations influence the movements and social interactions of wild deer and to
summarise, compare, and contrast the datasets from different collection sites. Approaches may
include network visualisations, stochastic blockmodelling, role analysis, latent space models, and
more. Results will allow researchers to predict how and why feeding stations effect wild deer
populations and ultimately inform conservation efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
