<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on MST Lab</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on MST Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Paper out in GENETICS</title>
      <link>/post/mosaic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mosaic/</guid>
      <description>Admixture is a pervasive and important element of human demographic history.
Summary Our new highlighted paper in the journal GENETICS deals with modelling complex human population histories. We&amp;rsquo;re particularly interested in something called &amp;ldquo;admixture&amp;rdquo;, which is when two or more previously separated populations come together, typically due to migration or the removal of some other barrier 1 to procreation between the groups. By examining modern genetic samples, we report evidence for such admixture globally and persistently, reflecting the importance of migration in shaping modern human populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview on Newstalk</title>
      <link>/post/coincidences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/coincidences/</guid>
      <description>Coincidences do happen. But what do they mean to us and just what are the chances? In this special feature episode, we find out&amp;hellip;
This was fun to take part in! Futureproof is a science programme on Newstalk hosted by @jonathan_mccrea. A special issue on Chance and Coincidence was recorded with input from Prof. Brian Hughes (@b_m_hughes (Professor of Psychology at the National University of Ireland, Galway ) and I.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SFI CRTs - PhD positions available</title>
      <link>/post/crts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/crts/</guid>
      <description>I am a named supervisor in two new Centre&amp;rsquo;s for Research Training funded by Science Foundation Ireland:
 Foundations in Data Science Genomics Data Science  These offer the fantastic opportunity to enter a fully funded PhD programme with a large cohort of other PhD candidates. Use the links to apply!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>